Andres Garza

Full-Stack Developer

San Antonio, TX 78254 **(832) 472-6611** garelan@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Trustworthy. Efficient, ethical individual with 10+ years of experience in the Administration/Medical Field. Currently working on transitioning to the Technology Industry as a Full-Stack Developer. Works great individually and as part of a team. Hard-working and committed. Easily adapt to new scenarios and tasks. Well-versed in communication and team building. Keen eyes for attention to detail.

EXPERIENCE

Methodist Healthcare System, San Antonio, TX — *Medical Assistant/Phlebotomist*

MARCH 2020 - PRESENT

- Directed patients to exam rooms, fielded questions and prepared for physician examinations.
- Assisted with routine checks and diagnostic testing by collecting specimens.
- Coordinated scheduling of patient procedures with Physicians' calendar to ensure physician's availability.
- Increased patient compliance by creating/implementing my own system for scheduling and reminding patients of their upcoming appointments.
- Scheduled pre-procedure testing required to safely perform the procedure.

Garden Bistro and Bar, San Antonio, TX — Assistant Manager/Administrator

FEBRUARY 2015 - MARCH 2022

- Used Microsoft Word and Microsoft Excel to create meeting minutes, reports and spreadsheets.
- Performed accounting activities by preparing expense reports, purchase orders and invoices.
- Monitored supplies to order and replenish stock when necessary.
- Initiated timely project management within budget constraints for multi-faceted problems concerning executive leaders.
- Reduced the amount of time required to perform after-shift duties by 20%
- Oversaw club operations.

EDUCATION

University of Texas at San Antonio, San Antonio, TX — Full-Stack Developer Bootcamp (Online)

JANUARY 2022 - PRESENT

University of Texas at San Antonio, San Antonio, TX — Bachelor of Liberal Arts in Psychology

AUGUST 2006 - MAY 2011

SKILLS

Problem-Solving
Attention to Detail
Staff Supervision
Microsoft Office
Creativity
Creative Thinker
Critical Thinking
HTML
CSS
JavaScript/NodeJS
SQL
GitHub

LANGUAGES

- ENGLISH
- SPANISH

Wellmed Medical Management, San Antonio, TX — *Medical Assistant/Appointment Scheduler*

APRIL 2019 - JANUARY 2022

- Greeted visitors and initiated triage processes for clients to streamline patient flow.
- Placed new supply orders, managed inventory and restocked clerical spaces.
- Scheduled patient appointments in respective doctors' calendars.
- Completed administrative patient intakes with case histories, insurance information and mandated forms.
- Increased patient compliance by using effective communication skills.

Southwest Key Programs, San Antonio, TX — *Medical Coordinator*

MAY 2012 - JUNE 2018

- Coordinated with other healthcare providers to build healthcare plans for patient's specific needs.
- Discussed new medications and technologies specific to patient's conditions.
- Documented changes in patient health conditions and progress through scheduled check-ups and monitoring.
- Maintained detailed records of medical supplies and ordered supplies.
- Maintained professional demeanor while treating patients with respect and dignity.
- Monitored and inspected staff processes to eliminate hazards posed for both residents and staff while ensuring continuous compliance with regulations.
- Discussed medical histories with patients in effort to provide most effective medical advice.
- Decreased the chances of Medical Error Occurrences by implementing various safeguards and procedures.